仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
翻译:  冰蓝   洗七里   亲爱的小饭
翻译:  吃货丁小七   兔美   两个身份赛太公
校对:  风华绝代赛太公
时间轴:  三水
后期:  瓜瓜    总监： 怀念浓子的瓜瓜
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
摩  登
家  庭
第八季 第四集
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
手机APP搜索
人人影视字幕组
一键收藏网盘资源生活大爆炸 吸血鬼日记
西部世界 谍网 超女
美剧资源应有尽有
扫码即刻关注
Zimuzu特别推荐
马上关注微信人人美剧（rrmjapp）
太好了  我闻到了咖啡味
Oh, thank God, I smell coffee.
今早一起来就诸事...
This morning has gotten off to a bit of a rocky...
如恐怖电影一般
Horror Picture Show.
你对你的脸做了什么
What did you do to your face?
涂了点眼影  让我眼睛更突出
Just a little color, to make my eyes pop.
你眼球现在也吓"突出"了
Like yours are now.
现在是我们发现爸爸想变性的时候吗
Is this how we find out you're transitioning?
请别选择年轻女生的名字
Oh, please don't pick a young name.
这世界不需要个50岁的杰思敏
The world doesn't need a 50-year-old Jasmine.
相信我  上镜时看起来会很正常
Trust me, this'll look completely normal on camera.
刚收到的消息  我要上新闻了
This just in -- I'm gonna be on the news.
他们在做房地产市场的报道
They're doing a segment on the real-estate market,
而我是当地专家
and I'm their local expert.
交给你了  克莱尔
Back to you, Claire.
你上次上新闻造成的不良影响还困扰着我
I'm still reeling from the last time you were on the news.
人们找到了各种各样的方式来避暑
And while people have found all sorts of ways to beat the heat,
一名当地人用了"头脑"
one local man is using his head.
菲尔·邓菲  当地居民
外面很热吗  我没发现啊
Is it warm out? I hadn't noticed.
看来我得重新化妆[申请]了
Looks like I need to re-apply.
进小丑大学吗
To clown college?
海莉  跟他去
Haley, go with him.
确保他把脸上的东西全擦掉
Make sure he gets all that stuff off his face.
我会带上厨房纸巾跟玻璃刮
I'll pack paper towels and a squeegee.
我怎么回事啊  我觉得好晕啊[毛绒绒]
Ugh. What is wrong with me? I feel so fuzzy.
别太苛责自己了  只是手毛而已
Oh, stop being so hard on yourself. It's just arm hair.
我填不出这题纵横字谜
I can't figure out this crossword puzzle.
我觉得接吻病让我的脑子笨了
I -- I think mono turned my mind to mush.
线索是什么  也许我能帮忙
What's the clue? Maybe I can help.
谢谢  妈妈  笑一下感觉挺好的
Thanks, mom. Feels good to laugh.
有什么好笑的
What is so funny?
我是个博学的大学毕业生
I am a well-read college graduate.
我觉得我能解纵横字谜
I think I'm capable of doing a crossword puzzle.
好  教授
Okay, professor.
三个字  阿基米德的感叹
Six-letter word, Archimedes' exclamation.
我现在不喜欢你了
I don't like you right now.
我为什么想不出来啊
Ugh. Why can't I get this?
阿基米德的感叹
Archimedes' exclamation.
"找到啦"[这就是答案]
Eureka.
我们也许永远不知道那条线索的答案
We may never know the answer to that clue,
但这让我意识到  我在拼字游戏上
but it made me realize this was my chance
打败艾丽克斯的机会来了
to finally beat Alex at Scrabble.
我从未打败过她
I have never beaten her.
而她不是太有品的赢家
She's not the nicest winner.
我赢了  你输了
I win, you lose!
我赢了  我赢了  你输了
I win! I win! You lose! ?
赢赢赢
Win, win, win, win, win, win, win!
输输输
Lose, lose, lose, lose, lose!
-谢谢你的造餐  -不用谢  亲爱的
-Thank you for bweakfast. -You're welcome, sweetie.
你听到了吗  "造餐"
Did you hear that? "Bweakfast."
幸亏我们带他去言语治疗了
It's a good thing that we're taking him to speech therapy.
我希望大家明白他说的每一句话
I want everybody to understand every single thing he says.
你的"赖油蛋简"上想加橘子酱吗
Do you want marmalade on your brioche toast?
完全听不懂
Not a clue.
你将说话问题扼杀于摇篮中是正确的
You're probably right to nip that speech problem in the bud.
米奇尔口齿不清  而我们放任不管
Mitchell had a lisp we let slide.
现在一辈子都在想  要是管了会怎样
Now we got a lifetime of "What if?"
你这话太无礼了
That is so offensive.
口齿不清不会让你变同性恋
A lisp doesn't make you gay.
当同性恋才会让你口齿不清
Being gay makes you lisp.
我完成了朱丽亚音乐学院的申请视频
Well, I finished the video for my Juilliard application.
我觉得他们会为之虎躯一震
I think they're going to be blown away.
艺校  反正以后没工作还能去路边卖橘子
Art school, huh? Well, you can always sell oranges by the side of the road.
别听他的
Don't listen to him.
去上艺术学校吧  做个编剧
Go to your art school, be a playwright.
谢谢
Thank you.
只要你愿意  在这里住多久都行
You can live here as long as you want.
* 一个有艺术气质  博览群书  父母离异的孩子 *
* How does an artsy, well-read, child of divorce *
* 一个哥伦比亚人 *
* A Columbian dropped *
* 在被人遗忘的地方 *
* In the middle of a forgotten plot *
* 是在郊区里  他自信满满... *
* In suburbia with confidence and... *
你是从音乐剧《汉密尔顿》里抄的  对吧
You copied that from that play "Hamilton," right?
"抄"这个词用得不合适
I'm not sure "copied" is the word.
应该说是致敬
It's more of an homage.
我大概两周前在"杰说"里致敬过了
Well, I homaged it about two weeks on "Jay Talking."
你看了那一集  对吧
You saw that episode, right?
-好吧  -我用"大米布丁"
- Okay. - I rhymed "Rice pudding"
和演员"库巴·古丁"押韵
with "Cuba Gooding."
顺便说一句  两者都很美味
Both delicious, by the way.
天啊
Oh, good God.
有几千个恶搞版《汉密尔顿》的视频
There are thousands of "Hamilton" parodies,
一半都是大学申请视频
and half of them are college applications.
没事  孩子  也许有百老汇的纽约人
It's okay, Papi. Maybe the people in New York
没听说过音乐剧《汉密尔顿》呢
haven't heard about "Hamilton."
提早申请的截止日期就在明天了
The deadline for early admission is tomorrow.
在那之前我绝对做不出更好的影片了
I'll never come up with something great by then.
你会的  我会帮忙
Yes, you will, and I'll help.
你愿意帮我吗
You'd do that for me?
为你做什么都行  孩子
Anything for you, kid.
我得让这孩子成功离家读书
I got to get this kid out of the house.
他的那些疯狂怪癖
All his crazy quirks.
越远越好
The farther away, the better.
我一直在家里放海上学校的宣传册诱惑他
I keep leaving brochures around for schools at sea.
在帆船上环球航行一年  在海上读书的学校
好了  孩子  补充碳水化合物
All right, carb up, buddy.
干掉这些煎饼
Tackle these pancakes
如球赛到拼死一战的阶段一样
like it's fourth and goal on the one-yard line.
说得好  教练
Good one, Coach.
用橄榄球术语说事情让生活更有趣了
Life's more fun when you put stuff in football terms.
煎饼  好棒
Pancakes, yay!
实际上家里没有煎饼了
Oh, uh, we're actually out of those.
你可以吃剩下的
You can have the rest.
不  我在里面加了一些运动营养品
No, no! We put some performance supplements in there
你这种小姑娘吃了要出问题
that could mess with you as a lady.
还剩什么能吃的吗
What else is there?
我晚点会去商店
Well, I'm going to the store later.
这之前你可以吃点水果
In the meantime, you can have some fruit.
那是真的吗  我还以为只是装饰品
That's real? I thought it was just for show.
自从我的明星球员德怀特的父亲
My star player Dwight has been living with us
转到佛罗里达州驻扎后  他就跟我们住
ever since his father was transferred to an army base in Florida.
他父亲在为我们国家做贡献
He's doing his part for our country,
所以我觉得我也能为我们球队做点贡献
so I thought I could do my part for our team.
有谁能说哪一种贡献更伟大呢
Who's to say who the bigger hero is.
我能  他更伟大
I will. He is.
我得提前半小时起床用洗手间
I've had to wake up a half hour earlier to use the bathroom --
军人更伟大
The soldier is the hero.
我们该怎么办呢
Ugh. What are we gonna do?
亲爱的  我知道
Oh, sweetie, I know.
-准备好了吗  -是的
- Ready to go? - Yes! Yes!
德怀特要和我去购物
Dwight and I are going shopping.
他要帮我挑双帅气的鞋
He's gonna help me pick out some cool new kicks.
就像李察·基尔带茱莉亚·罗伯茨去购物那样
Like Richard Gere taking Julia Roberts to the store.
没错  我们昨晚看了电影《风月俏佳人》
That is right. We watched "Pretty Woman" last night.
去购物的同时带我去吃饭不是挺好吗
I guess that would've been my window to eat something.
好吧  别动  你的眼窝非常深
Okay, hold still. You have very deep-set eyes.
大学的时候他们称我为小浣熊
In college, they called my "The Raccoon".
不过那也有可能是因为我
Although, that could've been because I climbed in
从狗洞钻进学生会的楼偷吃了一个派
through the doggy door at Zeta house and stole a pie.
天哪
My God.
我太美了
I'm beautiful.
亲爱的  你能靠这个吃饭了
Honey, you could do this for a living.
我有想过的
I have thought about it.
从卢克三岁开始我就经常在真人身上练习了
I've been practicing on people since Luke was 3.
我勒个去
Mo-o-o-o-ther nature.
你肯定不相信自己背后站的是谁
You're not gonna believe who's behind you.
-雷纳·向恩  -谁啊
- Rainer Shine! - Who?
天气预报员  你都不看新闻的吗
The weatherman. Don't you watch the news?
加油站等加油时看
Yeah, at the gas station.
他过来了  你赶紧...
He's coming this way. Just...
你要注意了
Whoa, careful now.
我的合同里有规定
There's a stipulation in my contract --
我必须是这里最帅的男人
I have to be the best-looking guy here.
不要调戏人家啦
Stop it.
雷纳·向恩
Rainer Shine.
真的很高兴见到你
It's, just, s-so nice to meet you.
那不是你的真名对吧
That isn't your real name, is it?
我就为你们揭开谜底吧
Ow, I'm not letting you behind that curtain.
的确是我真名  这牙也的确是真牙
That's my name, and these are my teeth.
我叫菲尔·邓菲
My name's Phil Dunphy.
节目有个房地产环节邀请我来
I'm doing a little real-estate segment.
有可能会变成常驻
Could become a regular thing.
这是我的化妆师及女儿  海莉·邓菲
This is my make-up artist/daughter, Haley Dunphy.
幸会  我觉得
It is a pleasure. You know, I think
是你帮我邻居桃瑞丝·雅各布卖的房子
you sold my neighbor's house -- Doris Jacobs.
白[人]  上世纪中[年]建成  "后庭"很大的吗
Uh, white, mid-century, big back porch?
就是她
That's her.
我想去洗个手  能告诉我洗手间在哪吗
I need to wash my hands. Where's the restroom?
当然  你穿过走廊
Oh, of course. You're gonna want to
推开那扇巨大的双开门
go down that hallway, push through the big double doors.
你会看到旁边有一些通风口
You're gonna see some air vents on the way there.
经过空气冷却系统[冷气团]就是了
It's just past that cold-air system.
带件外套
Bring a sweater.
那一带温度可能会有些低
It tends to get a little chilly in that neck of the woods.
跟你聊天很开心  菲尔
Nice shooting the breeze with you, Phil.
我也是  听我说
You too. Hey, uh, listen.
我知道可能有点突兀
This might be kind weird,
不过你想跟我去喝一杯吗
but would you ever want to grab a beer?
当然  感觉会很有意思
Sure. Sounds like fun.
好的
All right!
给  打三次电话给我
Here you go. Oh! C-- call me three times.
开玩笑的
I'm kidding.
一次就够了  如果你今晚有空的话
Just call me once. Tonight -- if you're around.
我看看能不能把你挤进我未来十天预测中
I'll see if I can squeeze you into my 10-day outlook.
好吧
Okay.
百闻不如一见啊
Do meet your heroes.
你准备得怎么样了
What have you got?
有什么能让朱丽亚音乐学院为你转身
What says to Juilliard, "I'm your guy"?
我盯着摄像头说
I look straight into the camera and say,
"莫里哀  贝克特  迪尔加多"
"Moliee, Beckett, Delgado."
前两者都是伟大戏剧编剧与作家
没错  把我的名字加进去是很大胆
Yes, it's bold to include my own name,
但人类第一次在白纸上写字也是如此大胆啊
but so is the sheer act of putting pen to paper.
你在开玩笑吧
You're kidding, right?
怎么了  哪里不对
Why? What's wrong?
这太自恋自傲自大了
It's smug and privileged and precious.
没有哪间艺校会喜欢的
No art school's gonna want that.
好吧  那这样呢
Okay. How about this?
我们打开一张白纸
We open on a blank sheet of paper.
在莫扎特的背景乐里  我们突然看到一滴血
Under a Mozart fugue, we suddenly see a drop of blood.
是录取委员会在割腕吗
Is it the admissions committee slitting their wrists?
好吧
Fine.
年代是在18...
The year is 18--
不  你找错方向了
No! You're on the wrong track here.
喜欢艺术的小屁孩儿们
They're gonna get a million applications
给他们寄了几百万份申请
from artsy little snots.
你必须与众不同
You've got to stand out.
当所有人都向左  你得挖地道
When everybody else zigs, you've got to zoink.
正常不是应该向右吗
Isn't it "Zag"?
所以啊
Exactly.
-你好  -我们回来了
- Hi. - We're back.
我不知道你们怎么回事  但我很喜欢
I don't know what this is, but I love it.
前门外有泥  德怀特坚持要抱我跨过
There's mud out front, so Dwight insisted.
好像这种帅鞋弄脏之后就不帅了
Apparently, they're not cool after you get them dirty.
昨晚我们还看了《军官与绅士》
Last night, we also watch "An Officer and a Gentleman."
没错  他把我举到"上面属于我的地方"
Yeah, he lift me up where I belong.
电影《军官与绅士》的主题曲名
片中有女主被男主新娘抱到空中的名场景
-好了  -我进来了
- Okay. -Knock, knock!
你好啊  帕斯特纳克女士
Yeah. Hi, Ms. Pasternack.
我得去见几个朋友
I got to go meet some friends.
-一会儿见  -好的  慢走  德怀特
- I'll see you guys later? - Okay. Be careful, Dwight.
给你  我又带了些酒瓶
Here. I brought by some more liquor bottles
给莉莉做设计
for Lily's project.
什...什么设计
Wha-- wh -- what project?
不知道  我发现她在我车库里翻翻找找
I don't know. I caught her going through my garbage,
她说她需要酒瓶
and she said she needed liquor bottles.
太奇怪了
Well, that's weird.
总之告诉她我明天会再拿几个给她
Anyway, tell her I'll have a couple more for her tomorrow.
好  拜拜  保重哦
Okay. Bye-bye. Take care.
以后不能再请她照顾莉莉了
She can't baby sit anymore.
什么设计
What project?
不知道
I don't know.
我们有麻烦了
We've got a problem here.
看看我在德怀特床底下发现了什么
Look what I found under Dwight's bed.
对啊  太可惜了
Yeah, it's too bad.
难得他给我们家带来那么多正能量呢
He brought such a great energy to the house.
米奇尔
Mitchell.
给我几秒时间想想怎么做
I just need a minute to process this.
买房小贴士
菲尔·邓菲  房产经纪人
但是凯伦  你的观众无论如何都该与
But the bottom line, Karen, is, your viewers should work with
他们能够信任的房产经纪人合作
a realtor they can trust.
一个能直视双眼  坦诚以对的人
Someone they can look in the eye.
我没懂  你想我看你总看错镜头吗
I'm confused. You wanted me to see that?
电视台有人还说我天生适合干这个呢
Well, someone there said I was a real natural.
是谁来着....
I can't remember who it was.
没错  是雷纳·向恩
Oh, that's right -- Rainer Shine.
那个媚俗的天气预报员吗
The cheesy weatherman?
不是  是拿过大奖的气象学者
No, the award-winning meteorologist.
他连续两届获得金牌[尿浴]播报员奖
He's the recipient of back-to-back Golden Showers.
不可能真叫这个...
That cannot be the actual name --
相当于他们的奥斯卡
It's their Oscars.
反正我给了他我的号码
Anyway, I gave him my number.
他给我打了电话
He called.
我们今晚要去喝酒
We're grabbing drinks tonight.
-没什么了不起的  -的确
- No big deal. - I agree.
拜托  我们都知道这可不得了啊
Please. We both know it's a super big deal.
我很高兴你认识了个新朋友
I am happy that you have a new friend.
享受一些纯爷们时刻应该不错
Be good to have some guy time.
没错
Yeah. Well...
我的妆
My makeup.
我的牌里有三个D了
I have, like, three D's.
双方抽出随机字母牌若干  在板上拼出单词
使用冷门字母  或拼出长字会有较高分数
比你以前带回家的成绩单
Well, it's better than any report card
上面的分数还高了
you ever brought home.
你们在干嘛
What are you guys doing?
还能是在跳伞吗
Skydiving.
我知道他的愚蠢是从哪遗传的了
Ugh. I see where he gets it from.
他想出答案后再叫我起床
Wake me when it's my turn.
还以为我能趁他病  要她命  赢她一把
I thought I could finally beat her because she's sick.
我真的好想她输啊
I just want her to lose so bad.
是啊  我也是
Yeah. So do I.
换牌作弊吗
Cheating?
我们真要出这招吗
Are we really doing this?
我们得打击打击你姐的嚣张气焰
That smug sister of yours needs to be taken down a peg.
接气焰[peg]
Ooh! Peg.
想更长更高分的
Think bigger.
气焰啊[pegs]
Pegs.
好了  乔  跟我读
Okay, Joe, repeat after me.
红色海盗船  红色海盗船  红色海盗船
Red rover, red rover, red rover.
王色歪盗床  王色歪盗床  王色歪盗床
Wed wovah, wed wovah, wed wovah.
好  现在我要你大大地微笑
Okay, now I want you to try it
然后再说出来
with a big smile on your face.
红色海盗船  红色海盗船  红色海盗船
Red rover, red rover, red rover.
抱歉  就是有时候我觉得
I am sorry. It's just sometimes I feel
我的口音有点...
like my accent gets a little
会影响到弗汉希欧·乔瑟夫
and it's gonna rub off on Fulgencio Joseph.
你不该怪自己啊
Well, you shouldn't blame yourself,
如果我没听错你说的话
if that's what you just said.
其实我这里还有一些练习可以帮到你
I actually have some exercises that can help you.
比如炮兵怕把标兵碰
Like Betty bought a bit of butter,
标兵怕碰炮兵炮
but found the butter bitter.
炮兵怕把飘乒蹦
Betty bought a bit 'a bootie,
标乒怕蹦抱兵抱
but da bootie bittah.
这一带治安不太好啊  杰
This is a pretty bad neighborhood, Jay.
我们要讲述的故事是这样的
This is the story that we're telling --
好斗的小孩  出身贫困
scrappy young kid, born into poverty
面临着种种困境
with the deck stacked against him.
我富到能补习书法呢
I have a calligraphy tutor.
下车  我要开始拍了
Hop out. I want to start shooting.
你就坐在车上吗
Hey, you're staying in car?
我一边开车一边拍你啊
I'm gonna drive alongside and film you.
快去吧  非常安全啦
Go ahead. It's perfectly safe.
你刚锁车门了吗
Hey. Did you just lock the door?
这车一关门就会自动锁上
The car does that automatically.
给你  试试这顶发网
Here. Try on this hair net.
这是不是有点太浮夸了啊
Isn't this a little over the top?
你觉得电影《为人师表》太浮夸了吗
Was "Stand and Deliver" over the top?
对啊  的确
Yes, it was.
行  那你就表现出生气的样子
Fine, then act angry, like you're sick of
像你受够了总被白人颐指气使
taking orders from the white man.
这个有经验我能演
Yeah, that I can do.
沿着那堵墙走  然后读台词
Walk along that wall, read from your script.
走吧
Go.
大家好
Hola!
"欢迎来到被我称为家的街区
"Welcome to the streets I call home.
世道艰险  所以我得更硬汉一些
It's tough out here, so I've had to be tougher.
因为在这个暴力当钱用
Because in a place where violence is currency
伤痛为好友的地方"
and pain is your best friend..."
这太丢人了  求你别拍了
Okay, this is embarrassing. Please don't shoot this.
你表现得很好
You're doing good!
假装你正从墙那边爬过来
Hey, pretend like you're climbing over the wall,
以防你之后想说是在墨西哥拍的
in case we want to say this is Mexico.
不会的
Not gonna happen.
好吧
Fine.
给你几罐喷漆
Here's some spray-paint.
用喷漆喷出你对美国佬的看法
Bubble letter me something about gringos.
不知道会是谁
Oh, I wonder who that could be.
警官你好
Oh, Officer.
有什么问题吗
Is there a problem?
我是来以未成年人饮酒的罪名
I'm here to arrest Dwight Bullock
逮捕德怀特·布洛克的
for underage drinking.
我们想给莉莉一个自己承认错误的机会
We wanted to give Lily a chance to come clean on her own.
幸亏我们有个朋友的朋友
Luckily, we have a friend of a friend
因为工作需要总穿着警服
who dresses as a cop for work.
他的工作也需要他把警服脱光
He also undresses as a cop for work.
记住  装作很难过就好了  知道吗
Remember, just act upset, okay?
好的
Okay.
德怀特·布洛克
Dwight Bullock.
我必须逮捕你
I have to arrest you.
因为你坏坏
You've been a bad boy.
但我什么都没做
But I didn't do it!
我是无辜的
I'm innocent!
我不知道为什么那个酒瓶会在我床底下
I don't know how that bottle got under the bed!
不用难过到这么浮夸
Now we're gonna take it down a notch.
伸出手来
Hold out your wrists.
我得带你到菊里走一趟
I've got to take you downtown.
德怀特  我对你太失望了
Dwight, I am very disappointed in you.
你不能再打橄榄球了
There's no more football.
你不能再上学了
No more school.
莉莉  在德怀特被关进监狱前
Lily, is there anything you'd like to say to Dwight
你有什么想对他说的吗
before he's taken to jail.
有吧
I guess.
玛莎·斯图尔特说过她利用狱中的时间
Martha Stewart said she used the prison time
美国家政女王  曾因内线交易而入狱
来充实自己
to work on herself.
够了  我们知道
That is enough! W-w-we know
是你把酒瓶放到德怀特床下的
you put the bottle under Dwight's bed.
你必须现在就向他道歉
You owe him an apology this minute.
这不公平
It isn't fair!
他吃啥啥不剩  还总占着厕所
He eats everything, he's always in the bathroom,
你们和他一起看电影  买衣服
you're watching movies with him, shopping with him.
你们两个都不爱我了
And you two don't even love me anymore!
-莉莉  -不是那样的
- Lily! - That is not --
莉莉  宝贝
Lily, honey!
你这玩意有钥匙吗
Do you have the keys to these?
我通常会让雇我的人伸手到我裤裆里找
I usually let the person who hired me find it in my pants.
那我就入境"随俗"吧
Well, if that is the custom, I --
米奇尔你够了
Mitchell.
我的天  又尿啊
Oh, my God. Again?
膀胱有多小  头脑就有多大
Small bladder, big brain.
不然我们怎么会打平手
That's why we're tied.
给我一个T  一个L和一个W
I need a "T," An "L," And a "W."
T  L
"T," "L"...
希望她困到不会注意到
Hopefully she's too sleepy to notice that she got
她板子上已经有三个w了
three "W"s on her board.
通常一轮游戏只会有两个w
另外  我想放屁
Also, can I take a pee?
好  要P就给你P
Yeah. Coming right up.
你有什么烦心事吗
Something wrong?
我差不多三小时前给雷纳发的短信
I texted Rainer, like, three hours ago.
他还没回复
He hasn't responded.
我相信他只是在装高冷难泡
I'm sure he's just playing hard to get.
这太奇怪了  我们昨晚聊得可开心了
It's just weird. We had such a great time last night.
我猜他肯定很忙
I bet he's busy.
他可是南加州的天气预报员啊
He's a weatherman in southern California.
他得时刻准备着
He has to be ready in case
万一温度猛降到"21度"以下立即报道
temperatures plunge below 70 degrees.
我告诉你  今晚可是有强风警告好吗
For your information, there is a wind advisory tonight.
说起来  我得去把风铃摘下来
In fact, I'm gonna go take down my chimes.
不是他吗
Not him?
不是  是我卖出去了幢房子
No. I sold a house.
他大概只是在吃晚饭而已
He's probably just having dinner.
他可能与佳人有约
He could be on a date.
他好像还挺风流的
Apparently, he's quite the player.
也不奇怪  哪有他撩不到的...
Makes sense. That could charm the pants off --
我勒个大去
What the what?!
爸
Hey, dad.
酷爹在此
There he is!
这是什么情况  你为什么在和他激吻
What is happening? Why are you kissing him?!
他晚饭时出手阔绰
He dropped some serious cash at dinner,
我就想  何乐而不为呢
so I figured, what the hell?
而你  你怎么能做出这种事
And you. How could you do this?
哪种事  其实我这
Do what? Actually, I'm -- I'm taking it
进展算慢的了  毕竟她是你女儿
kind of slow because she's your daughter.
对  她是我女儿  但你也能当她爸了
Yeah, she is, and she's half your age.
你卑鄙无耻下流
You're despicable.
好了  听我说一句  你好我是克莱尔
Oh, come on. Now, listen. Hi. Claire.
雷纳  请进  我们把话谈开
Rainer, come in. We'll just talk this out.
我很愿意  因为我不太明白...
I would like that because I -- I don't quite understand --
友情的意义吗
What friendship means?
菲尔  我也想把话说清楚
Look, Phil, I -- I want to figure this out,
但现在我不得不赶去查韦斯岭
but right now, I have to get to Chavez Ridge
报道这次强风事件
and cover this wind event.
让我告诉你
You know what?
我们友尽了
We're not friends.
你走
Go.
你出去
Get...
菲尔
Phil?
你太荒唐了
You're being ridiculous.
你真不把话说完吗
You really want to leave things like that?
从今以后
From now on,
我们只看特利西亚·田崎的天气预报
we're getting our weather from Tricia Tazaki!
吃葡萄不吐葡萄皮
Fred fed Ted bread.
不吃葡萄倒吐葡萄皮
Ted fed Fred bread.
你在干什么
What am I looking at?
乔的医生给了我几份演讲练习
Joe's doctor gave me some sp-heech exer-cises
来矫正我口齿不清的毛病
to help me speak more clear-ely.
但我怕我已经忘了原来怎么说话了
The problem is I fee-ear I have forgotten how I used to talk.
不用难过  你再差也差不过以前
Well, if it's any consolation, this isn't any worse.
曼尼 过来看下
Manny! Check this out.
我试着做了做你的视频
I think I took a stab at finishing your video essay.
在这个贫富差距巨大的世界
In a world divided into the haves and have-nots,
一名奇男子诞生了
a boy was born.
世界很残酷 我要变坚强
It's tough out here, so I've had to be tougher.
混街头  你不能相信任何人
On the streets, you can't trust anyone.
即便是最亲密的朋友都可能背叛你
Even your closest compadre could turn on you.
别开枪
Please don't shoot!
每天都是一场战...
Every day was a battle for your s--
我才不能发这个给音乐学院
I can't send this to Juilliard.
这都是你编的谎言
It's all lies.
这就对了 曼尼
That's right, Manny.
不要改变你自己  那样你会失去
Do not change who you are or you will lo-o-ose
自己的闪光点
what makes you spe-cial.
我的说话还这么怪吗
Am I still do-ing it?
这些也不全是我编的
They're not all lies.
你们俩给我讲过
I hear you the stories you two tell about
你们以前住的街区有多乱
the neighborhoods you lived in,
你在出租车后座上长大
growing up on the passenger seat of a cab.
的确  我是加入了我们专业人士成为"料"的东西
Sure, I put in what we professionals call "sizzle,"
但这些确实是你的亲身经历
but this is a part of who you are.
而且大家会更支持这种苦小子
And it's a lot easier to root for
而不是巧克力只吃含72%科科的富二代
than a kid who insists that 72% of his chocolate is cocoa.
是可可
It's "Cacao."
我相信他说的就是这点
I beliee-eve that is hiiis point.
你刚那是什么意思
What was that?
应该是我来问你话
How about I ask the questions.
你们俩什么时候谋划这次幽会的
When did you two set up this little rendezvous?
是趁我在节目上秒杀全场的时候吗
While I was killing it on the air?
他今天才给我打的电话
He called me today.
他怎么会有你的电话的
How'd he get your number?
他说是你给的
He said you gave it to him.
他这个大骗...
That lying sack --
我和我的化妆师约会了几次
Anyway, I dated my makeup girl for a while,
但后来她离开这城市了
but, uh, then she had to leave town.
我有个不情之请
Oh. Wow. Well, if -- if it's not crossing a line,
能把我女儿海莉的电话给你吗
can I give you my daughter Haley's number?
-真的吗  -真的  她现在正空窗
-Really? -Yeah, she's available,
而且她表达过兴趣
and she actually expressed some interest.
我也非常有兴趣
Well, I'm definitely interested.
那我们还等什么
Well, then let's make this happen.
菲尔·邓菲  你这人太赞了
Phil Denphy, you are the best!
这没啥
No.
我以为是让你去当化妆师
I thought it was about a makeup job.
我挺喜欢他的
I like him.
他是个好人
He's a good guy.
不  他不是好人
No, he's not.
他是全世界最赞的人
He's a great guy.
去追回他吧
Dad, run to him.
克莱尔  我去去就回
Claire, I'm going out!
认输吧  你没戏唱了
Admit it, it's over.
我领先你足足50分  而你只剩两个字母
I'm head by 50 points and you have two tiles left.
肯定还有能拼的高分字
There's got to be something!
我怎么就想不出来呢
I -- ugh -- Why can't I see it?!
半年前我还在加州理工  现在脑子像冻住...
Six months ago, I was at Caltech, and now -- ugh -- work.
放轻松  宝贝
Relax, honey.
这只是个游戏
It's just a game.
如果不只这么简单呢
What if it's more than that?
如果是这场病让我变傻了呢
What if mono permanently changed my brain?
一直以来我都以智商来定位自己
I've always defined myself by my intelligence,
如果连这都没了  那我还算什么
and if that's gone, who am I?
废柴输家
A loser.
卢克  别胡说
Luke! No!
我们作弊了
We cheated.
我们对牌动了手脚
Luke and I messed with the tiles.
-什么  -就是这样
What?! Yeah, it's just that,
你一直是家里的智商巅峰
you're the smartest one in the family,
却总是用智商羞辱我们
and you always rub it in,
我们也很郁闷啊
and it doesn't make us feel good.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
让你们这么郁闷  真不好意思
I feel terrible that I've been making you guys feel this way.
谢谢你坦白告诉我这些
Thank you for opening up to me about it.
不然我不会知道你们作弊了
Otherwise, I never would have known that you cheated,
这就说明
which means that...
我赢了你输了  我是天才你是笨蛋
I win, you lose! I win! You lose! I win! You lose!
我才是赢家
I win you lose.
累死了
God, I'm so tired.
如果你想剃光她的眉毛  动手吧
If you want to shave off her eyebrows, I'm cool with that.
莉莉  你在做什么
Lily, honey, what're you doing?
好的  第一次冷战
Okay. Her first ice out.
态度强硬一点
Be strong.
莉莉
G-- Lily.
好了好了  听我说
All right, all right, come on.
你对德怀特做的事是错的  知道吗
What you did to Dwight was wrong, okay?
我们对你很失望
We're very disappointed in you.
做错事就得受罚
Yes, and there's gonna be consequences.
一周内不许用电子设备
No electronics for a week.
这点你们比较怕  我没啥所谓
That'll be worse for you than for me.
那就一周没有点心
No dessert.
你戳中我的痛处了
Okay, that hurts.
话虽这么说  但这件事情上
That being said, we could've handled things
我们也有不好
a little bit better.
我们应该在德怀特搬来前
We should've talked to you
先和你商量一下
before having Dwight move in.
如果我不同意他就不会搬进来吗
You mean I could have stopped it?
倒也不是  但如果我们知道你不乐意
Well, no, but at least we would've know how you felt,
我们至少可以想办法让你不这么难受
and we could've made things easier for you.
宝贝  全世界我最理解你的心情
Sweetie, look, I, of all people, know what it feels like
那种失去众人关注的感觉
to go from being the center of attention --
我以前还在我父母家农场时体会过
I went through it with my parents back on the farm,
当时他们带回家一个6斤重的
when they brought home a seven-pound
粉色欢乐小可爱  然后对我说
little pink bundle of joy and said,
"你房间以后要跟他分享..."
"You're gonna share your room --"
我们都知道你说的是只小粉猪
We all know it's gonna be a pig.
总之  他还会打呼...
Anyway, he would snore...
好啦  对不起我说谎了
Okay, I'm sorry I lied.
谢谢  你真乖
Thank you.
你也得跟德怀特道歉
You have to apologize to Dwight, too.
我们吃饭的时候我会跟他说
I'll try to catch him in between bites.
我有个主意
Hey, I have an idea.
想一件能大家一起做的事
Let's think of something we can all do together, okay?
就我们四个人一起
Just the four of us.
你想做什么都行
Anything you want.
什么都可以
Absolutely anything.
三年前  他们给了我一次"什么都可以"
Three years ago, they gave me an "Absolutely anything,"
这机会我浪费在买冰棍上了
and I wasted it on a Popsicle.
我不会再犯这样的错误
That was not gonna happen again.
这真是个好有爱的派对
Well, now, this is a lovely party.
太美妙的下午了
It's a splendid afternoon.
还要茶吗
More tea?
不了  谢谢  我杯里还满着
No thanks. My cup is still full.
才没有
No, it isn't.
可我都还没喝呢
But I didn't drink it all.
让你加你就加
Just take the tea.
总之  在被雷击过后
Anyway, after the lightening strike,
我头发卷了整整两年呢
I had the perm for, like, two years.
怎么样
How's that?
雷纳
Rainer!
菲尔
Phil.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
你不会是那种疯子追风者吧
You're not one of those storm chasers, are you?
电影《龙卷风》揭露了这行竞争激烈后就不是了
Not since the movie "Twister" exposed how cutthroat it is.
我是来向你道歉的
I came here to apologize.
你不用这样
Oh, you don't have to do that.
不  我得道歉
Yes, I do.
我自己误会你  还说了一堆
I was confused, and I said a bunch of stuff
冤枉你的坏话
that you didn't deserve.
的确如风暴过境伤到了我中部区域
It did hit me, right around the mid-section.
海莉已经够大  能自己做决定了
Listen, Haley's old enough to make her own decisions.
我很喜欢她  但如果跟她在一起你会不高兴...
I really like her, but if dating her is gonna be a problem...
我的确不喜欢这25岁的年龄差距
I don't love the 25-year age difference.
其实只有二十...
It's actually 20...
二岁
2 --
二十二岁差距
22.
但我真的很不想
Le-- I would just hate to think
因为我跟她在一起
that dating her meant that you and I
就不能跟你当朋友
still couldn't be, you know friends.
你还想跟我当朋友吗
You still want to be friends?
对啊
I do!
菲尔  我认识好多好多人
Phil, I know a million people,
但真心朋友却没几个
but I really don't have a lot of real friends.
体育新闻那个人也不是吗
Not even the sports guy?
每次广告结束后切回来现场
You guys are always laughing so crazy hard
你们都好像聊到很开心
out of the commercials.
奇普·菲尔德吗  全是假的
Chip Fielder? No. That's all fake.
跟特利西亚·田崎装关心收容所狗狗一样假
Fake as Tricia Tazaki's shelter dogs!
兄弟  小心点
Careful, buddy.
你该走了
Look, maybe you should go.
我哪都不去
I'm not going anywhere!
我马上要播报了  你跑进镜头里了
I'm going live in a second. You're in my shot.
我知道了  再联系
Oh. I get it. Call me.
再联系
Call me!
没错  史蒂夫  但你今晚
That's right, Steve, but you're gonna want
最好就别出来放风筝啦
to leave your kites at home tonight.
我"风"华绝代的天气预测  稍后回来
My wind-erful forecast right after this.
我的名字叫曼尼·迪尔加多
My name is Manny Delgado,
我有两个身份
and I'm two people.
我是一名移民母亲的儿子
I'm the child of an immigrant single mother,
她教我要相信自己  勇敢做梦
who taught me to believe in myself and dream big.
我也是一名商人的继子
I'm also the step-son of a businessman
他让我住进他家  也住进他的心
who opened his home and his heart to me
并亲自示范给我看
and showed me, by example,
怎么让那些梦想化作现实
how to make those dreams come true.
无论我是怎么样的人  无论我能有何贡献
Whatever I am, whatever I have to give,
都是这两个截然不同世界的心血结晶
is a product of these two very different worlds.
那些话感人到杰都有点落泪了
It was so sweet that Jay cried a little bit.
他是个好孩子
He's a good kid.
家里见不到他的身影是会有些奇怪
And it's gonna be weird around here without him,
但至少我最特别的小姑娘会一直陪伴我
but at least I'll always have my special girl.
你永远不会离开我  对吧  小宝贝
And you'd never leave me, would you, baby? Mm!
我想你知道
I just want you to know
我真的不介意你跟雷纳在一起
I'm really okay with you dating Rainer.
谢谢  老爸
Thanks, dad.
的确  他有间超棒的房子
Yeah, he's got a really nice house --
浴室里还有按摩浴缸
Jacuzzi tub in his bathroom.
别喜欢那个
Don't love it you know that.
往上看
Look up.
他有说到一款发胶
Hey, he mentioned this hair spray
里面就油跟一点海盐
that's just oil and a little sea salt.
那款主要是护发不是固定
Oh, that's more for conditioning that hold.
好吧  幸亏问了你
Okay, wow, that was a close one.
好啦
All right.
刷刷
Now, brush...
弄几下唇
blot...
美呆了
And beautiful.
谢谢你  乖女儿
Thanks, honey.
新闻还找你回去真是太好了
It is really great that they having you back on the news.
不是  我是去拍新的驾照照片
No no, I just giving a new drive licence's photo.